There is such thing as a mind to mouth connection.
Being able to think and then say what you're thinking
and still in the process of that sound coherent
is a skillset.
And just like any skill,
your mind and mouth connection can be trained.
So if you are really good at thinking,
but you're not really good at speaking your thoughts,
then what tends to happen is,
what I'm trying to describe is there's like a,
you know, it's kind of connected to your mouth
and that's how I used to do it.
I wasn't able to speak my thoughts
and have it come across concise, clear and coherent.
And if you ramble like this,
especially in high stake moments like a team meeting
or a performance review or a job interview,
then you're not going to
get the outcome that you desire.
I've spent over a decade teaching communication skills
to thousands of professionals
who struggle with this specific thing.
And in this video, I'm going
to show you the one exercise
that's had the biggest impact on myself
and many of my students.
To help them be able
to strengthen their mind and mouth connection
so they can speak their thoughts with ease.
It's called the, wait for it,
the random word generator exercise.
I know, how creative of me.
Go to a random word generator online,
generate a random word and then speak on that topic.
Once you know how this works
and you do it just once,
you immediately notice where you struggle
and you want to do it
again and again and again and again.
This is all in the reps.
And the more reps you do,
the better you'll be able
to speak your mind with clarity.
So when your boss puts you on the spot
and you have to speak about a certain topic
or someone maybe pulls you aside
and asks you a random question,
you'll be able to speak your mind without lagging.
This is the random generator
and you can go to randomgenerator.com literally.
And if you hit the blue button,
it will generate a random word.
So can you see the word to the right there?
Right now it's cultural.
I'll click a random word and
then I'm going to talk on it.
Here we go. Random word.
Grave.
Now I have to speak on the word grave
for at least a minute to three minutes.
I still remember there was a book that I read
and the book said,
the richest place on earth is the graveyard.
And I was like, what?
What does that even mean?
That doesn't make sense.
And then the author further explained that
the reason why the graveyard
is the richest place on earth
is because so many people,
live their lives in desperation.
And they fear what other people think.
And as a result, they
don't bring their dreams to life.
So when they die, all of their dreams,
their ideas all die with them.
So when you go to the graveyard,
it's the richest place on earth.
It's the wealthiest place on earth
because there are inventions that were never invented
because that person was scared of what other people think.
There was impact that never was realized,
because people didn't learn how to use their voice
and bring their ideas to life.
There are visions, there are dreams,
there are gifts and talents that are all buried
with the person who unfortunately died.
And that has always stuck with me
because I never thought about it that way.
And it just goes to show the power of communication
because even though that communication
was in the written form,
that book and then the
book I read it from was,
it's inspired millions of people around the world.
And it just goes to show that communication,
no matter verbal or written,
it has the power to change the world
because it was that metaphor alone.
It was that analogy alone
that made me rethink my life.
I didn't want to go to the grave
with all of my ideas, all
of my dreams, all of my impact.
I wanted to live full and die completely empty
because I want my grave slot
to be the poorest place in the graveyard.
I want to live full and die completely empty.
All right, so that's an example of me
just speaking my mind, right?
And you have to appreciate
that while you're practicing this,
it will never be crystal clear wisdom.
Now this is you practicing speaking your mind.
There are more techniques to
be able to speak your mind
in a more structured way.
And that's by you learning
how to use communication frameworks.
I've recorded a free two hour training on this,
which you can access via the link in the description
or the pin comment below.
And when you practice the random word generator exercise
combined with the knowledge of communication frameworks,
oh, you're going to become a communication master.
So do check out the free training
when you finish this video.
I didn't know the word
grave was going to come up.
I had no idea that this is genuinely random.
So then as a result, I
was able to still be fairly eloquent.
I was able to still be fairly concise
and I was able to still be fairly coherent.
The first time I did this,
no way was it like this.
I'll give you a sense of what it was like.
The first time I did this,
I'll go back to the screen.
Let's get another one.
I'll give you a sense of what it was like.
It was like eliminate,
eliminate,
eliminating people, you know,
in sports that sometimes happens because,
you know, like dodge ball,
someone throws a ball at
you and then you get eliminated.
You know, eliminate.
You know, it's like game shows, people in game shows,
you know, you get eliminated.
And that's how I used to do it.
And when you do it for the first time,
it's going to be like that too.
It's going to be like that too.
And that's okay.
Most people are not willing
to pay the price of being
crap to then ultimately become great.
The reality is most people want to start out great.
And then as a result, they don't start at all
because it's impossible to start great.
You must start poorly.
Anything worth doing is worth doing poorly.
Inside the stage community, we have
an area called the practice lounge.
So many students upload videos every
single day of them doing the mind
and mouth connection going, okay, the random word is monkey.
Oh crap, I got to talk about monkey.
And then they're talking about monkey.
And you'll see their first video.
You'll see their second video.
You'll see their third video, fourth video.
And you'll start to notice they
get better and better and better.
Why?
Because they're starting to strengthen
the mind and mouth connection.
And if you don't practice, well,
you'll never have that strong connection.
And you will always forever be in
a state where someone asks you a question.
You know the answer, you know the answer in
your mind, but then you go, well, I think it's,
um,
and then you just fall apart.
Well, that's because the connection is not strong.
It's not because you're not capable.
It's not because you didn't know the answer, but rather because
you haven't worked on a skill that has been holding you back.
So I need you to understand that as you're going on the journey of strengthening your mind
and mouth connection, please, please, please, please don't beat yourself up when you do the first one.
And it's absolutely terrible.
Record a video of yourself on your computer, and then you just do a selfie video
and you go, all right, I'm about to hit, I'm about to hit the random word.
So I'm genuinely going to do this.
Click random words, show the word on the phone.
And then go.
All right, I'm going to
talk about pigeons and then go.
99% of people won't do this exercise.
So if you do it, post it on social media and tag
me at ask Vin and hashtag the hashtag Vin's random word challenge.
I know I'm just super creative.
I'm amazing.
And I'll check it out.
I might even share it.
And if, listen, you want to take this to the next
level, then make sure you combine that exercise with communication frameworks.
And if you want to access that free
training, the link is just in the description.
And I'll remind you of the quote again.
In order for you to become great,
you first must be a little bit crap.
Or as I like to say,
you must be a little bit shit.
I know.
Potty mouth.
So naughty, Vin.
So naughty.
It's who I am.